<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://tommyd206.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://tommyd206.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-01-31T18:42:02+00:00</updated><id>https://tommyd206.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">terraform</title><link href="https://tommyd206.github.io/blog/2025/code/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="terraform"/><published>2025-01-31T10:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-31T10:15:00+00:00</updated><id>https://tommyd206.github.io/blog/2025/code</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tommyd206.github.io/blog/2025/code/"><![CDATA[<p>Functional Requirements Infrastructure Provisioning: Automate the creation of an Azure account, including resource groups, networking, identity management, and security configurations using Terraform. State Management: Store Terraform state securely using Terraform Enterprise’s PostgreSQL backend and Azure Storage Accounts, ensuring no customer state is co-located. Encryption: Enable encryption at rest for all storage accounts and PostgreSQL databases using Azure-managed keys or customer-managed keys (CMK). Identity and Access Management (IAM): Configure Azure Active Directory (AAD) roles and permissions to enforce least privilege access for Terraform workflows. Logging and Monitoring: Enable Azure Monitor, Log Analytics, and Terraform Enterprise audit logs for tracking infrastructure changes and access patterns. Networking Security: Restrict Terraform state storage and PostgreSQL database access using private endpoints, service endpoints, and network security groups (NSGs). Secrets Management: Store sensitive credentials (e.g., service principal secrets) securely in Azure Key Vault and retrieve them dynamically within Terraform workflows. Deployment Workflow: Implement CI/CD pipelines (e.g., GitHub Actions, Azure DevOps) to validate and apply Terraform configurations in a structured and automated manner. Non-Functional Requirements Security &amp; Compliance:</p> <p>Ensure end-to-end encryption for all data at rest and in transit. Enforce RBAC policies to prevent unauthorized access. Implement audit logging for compliance with industry standards (e.g., HIPAA, SOC2). Scalability:</p> <p>Support multi-tenant environments without co-locating customer state in shared storage. Allow dynamic scaling of Terraform Enterprise’s PostgreSQL database and storage backend. Reliability &amp; Availability:</p> <p>Design for high availability, ensuring zero downtime for state storage and Terraform Enterprise. Implement backup and disaster recovery for PostgreSQL and storage accounts. Performance:</p> <p>Optimize Terraform runs to complete within defined SLAs. Minimize API rate limits and latency issues with Azure resource provisioning. Maintainability:</p> <p>Use modular Terraform configurations to enable reusability and ease of updates. Implement automated testing and validation for Terraform modules before deployment. Cost Optimization:</p> <p>Use reserved instances or autoscaling where applicable to reduce cloud costs. Monitor Terraform execution costs and storage utilization with Azure Cost Management.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="infra"/><category term="terraform"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[automating infra e2e with terraform]]></summary></entry></feed>